<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Life As I Know It!</title>
    <link>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Life As I Know It!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 07:05:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let It Go</title>
      <link>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/let-it-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 07:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/let-it-go/</guid>
      <description>In our lives we get attach to a lot of things. We hold on to material things. We hold on to our old conceptions, opinions and prejudices. Developing this sort of attachment is common. Often this is needed. Commitment, dedication and perseverance are needed to succeed in our professional and personal lives. But at times we must let these things go. We must refine our understanding and if needed change our course of action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BenchmarkDotNet</title>
      <link>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/benchmarkdotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 07:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/benchmarkdotnet/</guid>
      <description>While developing software, we often have the need to benchmark some implementations and compare the performance. Every benchmarking task has common boiler plate code which is tedious and repetitive. BenchmarkDotNet helps in avoiding this boiler plate code and focus on the code which needs to be benchmarked.
How to do benchmarking using BenchmarkDotNet I generally make a standalone app to run the benchmarks. The standalone app needs to take a dependency on BenchmarkDotNet nuget package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Programming Resources</title>
      <link>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/competitive-programming-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 06:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://soubhagyarnayak.github.io/posts/competitive-programming-resources/</guid>
      <description>Competitive programming has been always appealing to me. I used to consider it as one of my hobbies. I have blogged about my experience and the reason for participating in Google CodeJam in this post. Of late I am not able to find time due to personal and professional work. The following are some really nice competitive programming resources.
Online Contests  Google CodeJam Top Coder Facebook Hacker Cup Code Forces Yandex Contest  MOOCs  Competitive Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Core Skills How to Win Coding Competitions: Secrets of Champions  Books  Competitive Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Handbook  Training  Top Coder tutorials Yandex Contest Tutorials ITMO University Training Center  Problem Sets  Sphere Online Judge Timus Online Judge  Contest for Students  ACM ICPC IOI  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
